American Goulash

Ingredients

1 tablespoon olive oil
2 pounds ground beef
1 large onion, diced
4 cloves garlic, minced
2 large bay leaves
2 tablespoons paprika
2 teaspoons Italian seasoning
2 teaspoons kosher salt
1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper
1 pinch cayenne pepper, or to taste
1 quart chicken broth
1 (24 ounce) jar marinara sauce
1 (15 ounce) can diced tomatoes
1 cup water
2 tablespoons soy sauce
2 cups elbow macaroni
1/4 cup chopped Italian parsley
1 cup shredded white Cheddar cheese (Optional)

Directions

Gather all ingredients.
Heat oil in a pot over medium-high heat. Add ground beef and onion; cook and stir until beef is browned and crumbly and onion is translucent, about 5 minutes. Continue to cook and stir until liquid is evaporated, 3 to 5 minutes. Add garlic, bay leaves, paprika, Italian seasoning, salt, black pepper, and cayenne.
Cook, stirring occasionally, until flavors come together, about 3 minutes. Pour in broth, marinara sauce, and diced tomatoes. Pour water into the sauce jar, swirl, and pour into the pot. Stir in soy sauce; bring to a simmer. Reduce the heat to medium and simmer until flavors intensify, about 30 minutes.
Increase the heat to medium-high and bring to a rapid simmer. Stir in macaroni; cook, stirring occasionally, until just barely tender, about 12 minutes. Check for doneness after 10 minutes.
Remove from the heat and discard bay leaves. Stir in cheddar cheese and parsley. Cover and let rest for 5 minutes. Taste and season as desired.

Banana Bread

Ingredients

Banana Bread

8 ounces cream cheese, at room temperature
1 large egg
1/4 cup sugar
2 tablespoons flour

Cream Cheese Filling

2 to 3 very ripe bananas, peeled (about 1 1/4 to 1 1/2 cups mashed)
1/3 cup (76g) melted butter, unsalted or salted
1/2 teaspoon baking soda
Pinch salt
3/4 cup (150g) sugar (1/2 cup if you would like it less sweet, 1 cup if you want it sweeter)
1 large egg, beaten
1 teaspoon vanilla extract
1 1/2 cups (205g) all-purpose flour

Directions

Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F and grease a 4x8-inch loaf pan.
Make the banana bread batter:
In a mixing bowl, mash the ripe bananas with a fork until completely smooth. Stir the melted butter into the mashed bananas.
Mix in the baking soda and salt. Stir in the sugar, beaten egg, and vanilla extract. Mix in the flour.
In another bowl, beat together all the ingredients for the cream cheese filling.
Pour half of the banana bread batter in the loaf pan. Top the batter with half of the cream cheese filling, one dollop at a time. Top with remaining batter. Top with the remaining cream cheese filling one dollop at a time. Insert a butter knife about halfway into the batter and run through the batter vertically and horizontally to swirl the cream cheese into the banana bread batter.
Bake for 55-60 minutes or until a toothpick inserted in the center of the loaf comes out clean.

BBQ Chicken

Ingredients

6 - 8 (1230g or 2.5 - 3lbs) chicken thighs or drumsticks
Your favorite BBQ sauce
Salt and black pepper to taste
1 cup (250ml) cold water
3 drops liquid smoke (optional)
1/2 teaspoon garlic powder (optional)
1/2 teaspoon onion powder (optional)
1/2 tablespoon white vinegar (optional)

Directions

Add Water and Steamer Basket: Add 1 cup (250ml) cold water and (optional) 3 drops of liquid smoke in Instant Pot Pressure Cooker. Then, place a steamer basket in the pot.
Pressure Cook Chicken: Generously season both sides of chicken with salt and black pepper, then layer chicken on stainless steel steamer basket. Close lid and pressure cook at High Pressure for 8 minutes, then 10 minutes Natural Release.
Spice Up BBQ Sauce: If you are using store-bought BBQ sauce, add more depth of flavor with some garlic powder, onion powder, and white vinegar. Taste and adjust accordingly.
Apply BBQ Sauce to Chicken: Pat dry chicken and place them on an oven tray. Generously coat both sides of chicken with BBQ sauce.
Caramelize Instant Pot BBQ Chicken: Place BBQ Chicken under the broiler for 4 - 8 minutes until the BBQ chicken is browned and caramelized.

BBQ Pulled Pork

Ingredients

Pork

4 pounds (1730g) pork shoulder (pork butt meat), cut into 2 - 2 1/4 inches cubes
1 tablespoon (15ml) olive oil or vegetable oil

Dry Rub

2 tablespoons (25g) brown sugar
2 teaspoons (5g) chili powder
2 teaspoons (4g) ground black pepper
1 teaspoon (2.4g) onion powder
1 teaspoon (2.8g) garlic powder
1 teaspoon (2.3g) cinnamon powder
1 teaspoon (3g) kosher salt
1/2 teaspoon (1g) cumin seed, ground
1/2 teaspoon (1g) fennel seed, ground
1/4 teaspoon (0.25g - 0.5g) cayenne pepper

BBQ Sauce

1 (200g) medium onion , sliced
1 tablespoon (12.5g) brown sugar
3 garlic cloves , minced
3/4 cup cup (188ml) unsalted chicken stock
1/8 cup (31ml) maple syrup or honey
1/8 cup (31ml) honey
2 tablespoons (30ml) apple cider vinegar
2 tablespoons (30ml) Dijon mustard
3 drops liquid smoke (optional)
1 cup (250ml) ketchup

Thickener

4 tablespoons (32g) all purpose flour or cornstarch
1/4 cup (63ml) cold tap water

Directions

Rub Pulled Pork Dry Rub: Mix all Dry Rub ingredients, then rub it all over the cubed pork. Put pork in fridge for 30 minutes up to overnight.
Saute Onion and Garlic: Heat up Instant Pot using "Saute" function.
Deglaze Instant Pot: Add 3/4cup (188ml) unsalted chicken stock in Instant Pot. Then completely deglaze the bottom of the pot by scrubbing the flavorful brown bits with a wooden spoon.
Add Seasoning and Pork: Add 1/8 cup (31ml) maple syrup, 1/8 cup (31ml) honey, 2 tbsp (30ml) apple cider vinegar, 2 tbsp (30ml) Dijon mustard, and 3 drops liquid smoke to the Instant Pot. Give it a quick mix. Place all cubed pork in Instant Pot. Layer 1 cup (250ml) of ketchup on top of the pork. Do not mix.
Cook Pork: With Venting Knob in Venting Position, close the lid, then turn Venting Knob to Sealing Position. Pressure Cook at High Pressure for 35 minutes, then Natural Release for 15 minutes. Open the lid carefully.
Check Pork Shoulder's Tenderness: Check if the pork is tender enough. If the pork is still tough, Pressure Cook at High Pressure for another 10 minutes. Remove pork from Instant Pot and set aside.
Thicken BBQ Sauce: Bring BBQ sauce to a simmer with "Saute" function. In a container, mix 4 tbsp (32g) all-purpose flour with 1/4 cup (63ml) cold water. Make sure to mix it really well. When BBQ Sauce is simmering, mix the flour mixture into the BBQ sauce one-third at a time until your desired thickness.
Season BBQ Sauce: Taste BBQ sauce and add more brown sugar or kosher salt as needed. For reference, we added 2 pinches of salt and 2 tsp brown sugar at the end to balance flavors. Taste test once more to make sure everything is perfectly seasoned.
Crisp Pork Shoulder: Coat pork cubes generously with BBQ Sauce. Place pork under a broiler or the top rack of a preheated 450 degrees F toaster oven until the surface is crisped (roughly 8 to 10 minutes). Flip the cubed pork, brush each piece with more BBQ sauce, then place them in oven again until the surface is crisped.
Shred Pork and Serve: Shred pulled pork with two forks and serve.

BBQ Ribs

Ingredients

1 rack (2 to 3 pounds) baby back ribs
2 Tablespoons dry rib rub
3/4 cup BBQ sauce
1 cup apple juice or water
1/4 cup apple cider vinegar
1 Tablespoon liquid smoke
1 Tablespoon salt

Directions

Rinse the whole rack of ribs in water and then pat dry with paper towels.
Remove the membrane (silver skin) from the boney side of the ribs by sliding a butter knife under the membrane on top of a bone and pulling up. Using your hands or a paper towel, remove the membrane completely.
Rub the dry rib rub all over the rack of ribs on both sides. (You can either cook the ribs right away or wrap them in plastic wrap and store in the refrigerator overnight before cooking.)
Place the metal rack (trivet) into the bottom of the pressure cooker insert. Add apple juice, apple cider vinegar, liquid smoke, and salt into the bottom of the pot.
Place the rack of ribs into the pot on top of the metal rack, standing them up on their side. Wrap them around the inside lining of the pot with the meaty side of the ribs facing outward.
Close the lid and lock into place. Set the pressure valve to "Sealing" and pressure cook on "Manual" high pressure for 25 minutes. Once done, allow pressure to naturally release for 10 minutes, and then quick-release the remaining pressure according to the manufacturer's instructions.
Using tongs, carefully remove the ribs and place onto a baking sheet.
Set your oven to "Broil" (or the highest temperature setting).
Generously brush ribs down with BBQ sauce on both sides. Place under the broiler for 5 minutes, until sauce is bubbly and starts to caramelize.
Slice into individual ribs before serving. Serve with extra BBQ sauce.

Beef Stew

Ingredients

1 1/2 Pounds Beef Stew Meat
1 Tablespoon Olive Oil
1 Teaspoon Salt
1 Teaspoon Pepper
1 Teaspoon Italian Seasoning
2 Tablespoons Worcestershire Sauce
3 Cloves Garlic, Minced
1 Large Onion, Chopped
1 16 Ounce Bag Baby Carrots, Cut Into Slices
1 Pound Potatoes, Cubed
2 1/2 Cups Beef Broth
1 10 Ounce Can Tomato Sauce
2 Tablespoons Cornstarch
2 Tablespoons Water

Directions

Add the olive oil to the instant pot and turn on the saute function. When the oil starts to sizzle add the meat and season with the salt, pepper, and Italian seasoning.
Cook the meat until Browned on all sides.
Add the beef broth to the instant pot and use a spoon to scrape the brown bits from the bottom of the pan.
Add the Worcestershire sauce, garlic, onion, carrots, potatoes, and tomato sauce.
Close the lid and steam valve on the instant pot.
Cook on high pressure for 35 minutes, then allow the pressure to release naturally for 10 minutes before doing a quick release.
Mix together the cornstarch and cold water in a small bowl and stir into the stew until thickened.

Cajun Pasta

Ingredients

16 oz rotini pasta (or any short pasta of choice)
1 lb shrimp, peeled and deveined
1 13 oz Andouille sausage
4 tbsp Cajun seasoning
2 tbsp olive oil
4 tbsp unsalted butter
1/2 medium yellow onion, sliced
6 cloves garlic, minced
2 cups heavy cream
2 cups milk
1/2 cup grated Parmesan cheese
1 cup shredded cheddar cheese
2 tsp smoked paprika
1 tsp red pepper flakes (optional, for extra spice)
1 tsp salt (adjust to taste)

Directions

Season shrimp and sausage with 2 tbsp Cajun seasoning.
Heat olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Cook the sausage until and fully cooked. Remove and set aside.
In the same skillet, melt 2 tbsp butter and cook the shrimp until pink and opaque, about 2-3 minutes per side. Remove and set aside.
Reduce heat to medium-low, then add minced garlic to the skillet. Saute for 1-2 minutes until fragrant.
Stir in heavy cream, milk, remaining butter, Parmesan cheese, cheddar cheese, smoked paprika, and the remaining Cajun seasoning. Mix well until the sauce is smooth and creamy.
Add the cooked pasta, chicken, and shrimp to the skillet. Toss to coat evenly with the creamy Cajun sauce.
Adjust seasoning with salt and red pepper flakes, if desired.

Carrot Cake

Ingredients

Cake

2 cups white sugar
1 1/4 cups vegetable oil
4 eggs
2 teaspoons vanilla extract
2 cups all-purpose flour
2 teaspoons baking soda
2 teaspoons baking powder
2 teaspoons ground cinnamon
1/2 teaspoon salt
3 cups grated carrots

Frosting

1/2 cup butter, softened
8 ounces cream cheese, softened
4 cups confectioners' sugar
1 teaspoon vanilla extract

Directions

Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). Grease and flour a 9x13 inch pan.
Beat sugar, oil, eggs, and 2 teaspoons vanilla together in a large bowl with an electric mixer until well combined. Mix in flour, baking soda, baking powder, cinnamon, and salt. Stir in carrots. Pour into the prepared pan.
Bake in the preheated oven until a toothpick inserted into the center of the cake comes out clean, about 40 minutes. Let cool in the pan for 10 minutes, then turn out onto a wire rack and cool completely.
To make the frosting: Beat butter, cream cheese, confectioners' sugar, and 1 teaspoon vanilla together in a large bowl with an electric mixer until smooth and creamy. Frost the cooled cake.

Cheddar Broccoli Soup

Ingredients

1/4 Cup Onion, diced
1/4 Cup Carrot, shredded
1 Clove Garlic, minced
3 Tablespoons Butter
1 Tablespoon Flour
1 Cup Chicken Broth, warm
1/2 Cup Water
2 Cups Broccoli, chopped in small pieces
1 Cup Heavy Whipping Cream, warmed
1 Tablespoon Cream Cheese
1 Cup Cheddar Cheese (sharp or mild)
Salt and pepper to taste

Directions

Begin by melting the butter (or ghee) in a large saucepan over medium heat. Add the onions and carrots and saute until they soften, approximately 3-4 minutes. Season with a little salt and pepper as they cook.
Add the garlic and saute another 30 seconds or until fragrant.
Add the flour and whisk for 1-2 minutes, stirring with a whisk. Slowly add the warmed chicken broth and water allowing the soup come to a boil. Turn the stove down to low (or take it off the heat entirely) and add the cream. Stir to incorporate.
Add the cream cheese and slowly add the cheddar cheese about 1/4 cup at a time, ensuring it has completely melted before adding any more.
Add the broccoli and taste for seasonings. Let the soup simmer 10 min or until broccoli softens.
Serve hot.

Chicken and Dumplings

Ingredients

Soup

2 tablespoons vegetable oil
2 lb boneless, skinless chicken breast, cubed
1 cup diced yellow onion
1 cup sliced carrot
3 cloves garlic cloves, minced
1 teaspoon salt
5 tablespoons unsalted butter
6 tablespoons all-purpose flour
6 cups chicken broth
1/2 cup heavy cream
1/2 teaspoon dried thyme
2 bay leaves
4 tablespoons fresh parsley, minced

Dumplings

2 cups all-purpose flour
1 tablespoon baking powder
1/2 teaspoon salt
1/2 teaspoon pepper
1 1/3 cups heavy cream

Instructions

In a 6-quart Dutch oven, heat the vegetable oil over medium-high heat. Add the chicken and cook until browned on both sides. Remove from the pot and set aside.
Add carrot and onion and cook until just tender, about 3 minutes.
Add the garlic and stir for another minute, until fragrant.
Reduce the heat to medium-low and add the butter and flour, stirring constantly for 3 minutes to prevent lumps from forming.
Add the chicken and any accumulated juices back to the pot and stir to coat in the roux.
Add the chicken broth, cream, thyme, and bay leaves and bring to a simmer. Once soup is at a simmer, add the frozen peas, cover, and cook for 15 minutes.
Make the dumplings: In a large bowl, combine the flour, baking powder, salt, pepper, and cream. Stir until mixture comes together into single mass of dough.
Using a large spoon or ice cream scoop, form the dough into small round balls about 1 inch (2 1/2 cm) in diameter (the dough should yield 14-16 dumplings).
Place the dough balls in the simmering soup (making sure they don't touch), add the parsley, and cover. Let the soup simmer for 15 minutes, or until the dumplings are cooked through.
Ladle into bowls, giving 1-2 dumplings per serving.

Chicken and Rice

Ingredients

2 boneless skinless chicken breasts (diced into 1 inch pieces)
2 Tbsp olive oil or butter
1 tsp minced garlic
1 tsp black pepper
1 tsp salt
1/2 onion (chopped)
1 3/4 cups chicken broth
1 can cream of chicken soup (10.5 oz can)
1 1/2 cups white rice
2 cups cheddar cheese (shredded)

Directions

Turn the instant pot to the saute setting and add in the olive oil.
Add the chicken and onions and cook for 5-7 minutes stirring occasionally until the onions are softened and the chicken is browned slightly.
Then add in the minced garlic and cook on the saute setting for 1-2 minutes.
Then stir in the rice. Make sure the rice is covered by the liquid (add more broth if needed).
Next pour the cream of chicken soup on top of the other ingredients but do not mix it in with the other ingredients.
Seal the instant pot (by moving the valve on the lid to the seal position). Cook on high pressure for 3 minutes. After the cook time, let the pressure release from the instant pot naturally by not moving the valve on the lid.
Once all the pressure has been released from the instant pot. Remove the lid, stir in the shredded cheese. The heat from the meal will melt the cheese.
Serve warm.

Chili Mac

Ingredients

1 tablespoon olive oil
1 pound extra lean ground beef
1 medium yellow onion, diced
1/2 medium red bell pepper, diced
4 cloves garlic, minced
3 1/2 tablespoons gluten-free taco seasoning mix
1/2 teaspoon salt
1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper
1 (15 ounce) can black beans, rinsed and drained
1 (14.5 ounce) can diced tomatoes
1 (8 ounce) can tomato sauce
1 cup water
2 cups beef broth
2 (8 ounce) packages quinoa elbow pasta
2 cups grated Cheddar cheese
1 tablespoon chopped fresh parsley

Directions

Turn on a multi-functional pressure cooker, add oil, and select Saute function. Add ground beef to the hot oil and saute until browned and crumbly, 5 to 7 minutes. Add onion, bell peppers, and garlic; saute for 2 more minutes.
Add, in this order, taco seasoning mix, salt, pepper, black beans, diced tomatoes, tomato sauce, water, beef broth, and pasta. Do not mix. Close and lock the lid. Select high pressure according to manufacturer's instructions; set timer for 4 minutes. Allow 10 to 15 minutes for pressure to build.
Release pressure carefully using the quick-release method according to manufacturer's instructions, about 5 minutes. Unlock and remove the lid. Stir in cheddar cheese and garnish with parsley.

Chocolate Peanut Butter Cake

Ingredients

Cake

1 and 3/4 cups (219g) all-purpose flour (spooned & leveled)
3/4 cup (62g) unsweetened natural cocoa powder
1 and 3/4 cups (350g) granulated sugar
2 teaspoons baking soda
1 teaspoon baking powder
1 teaspoon salt
1/2 cup (120ml) canola or vegetable oil
2 large eggs, at room temperature
3/4 cup (180g) full-fat sour cream, at room temperature
1/2 cup (120ml) buttermilk, at room temperature
2 teaspoons pure vanilla extract
1/2 cup (120ml) hot water or black coffee
1 cup (170g) mini semi-sweet chocolate chips (tossed in 1 Tablespoon flour)

Frosting

3/4 cup (12 Tbsp; 170g) unsalted butter, softened to room temperature
1 and 3/4 cup (440g) creamy peanut butter
1 and 3/4 cup (210g) confectioners' sugar
1 teaspoon pure vanilla extract
pinch of salt
3 Tablespoons (45ml) heavy cream or heavy whipping cream, at room temperature

Chocolate Ganache

8 ounces (226g) quality semi-sweet chocolate, finely chopped
1 cup (240ml) heavy cream or heavy whipping cream
chopped or mini peanut butter cups for garnish (optional)

Directions

Preheat oven to 350 F (177 C). Grease three 9-inch cake pans, line with parchment paper rounds, then grease the parchment paper. Parchment paper helps the cakes seamlessly release from the pans. (If it's helpful, see this parchment paper rounds for cakes video & post.)
Make the cake: Whisk the flour, cocoa powder, sugar, baking soda, baking powder, salt, and espresso powder (if using) together in a large bowl. Set aside. Using a handheld or stand mixer fitted with a whisk attachment (or you can use a whisk), mix the oil, eggs, and sour cream together on medium-high speed until combined. Add the buttermilk and vanilla and beat until combined. Pour the wet ingredients into the dry ingredients, add the hot water/coffee, and whisk or beat on low speed until the batter is completely combined. Fold in the flour-coated chocolate chips. Batter is thin and you may see some air bubbles on the surface-that's normal. You should have about 6-6.5 cups of batter, or around 1400g.
Divide batter evenly between 3 pans. Bake for approximately 24-26 minutes. Baking times vary, so keep an eye on yours. The cakes are done when a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean.
Remove the cakes from the oven and set on a wire rack. Allow to cool completely in the pan. The cakes may slightly sink in the middle as they cool-that's expected.
As the cakes cool, make the peanut butter frosting: With a handheld or stand mixer fitted with a paddle attachment, beat the butter on medium high speed until creamy and smooth, about 2 minutes. With a rubber spatula, scrape down the sides and bottom of the bowl as needed. Add the peanut butter and beat until completely combined, about 1-2 minutes. Scrape down the sides and bottom of the bowl as needed to help combine. Mixture will be thin. Add confectioners' sugar, vanilla extract, and salt and then pour in the heavy cream with the mixer running on low speed. After all of the cream has been added, turn the mixer up to medium-high speed and beat for 1-2 minutes, or until fully combined and creamy. Add up to 1/4 cup more confectioners' sugar if frosting seems quite thin. You should end up with about 3.5-4 cups (850g) of peanut butter frosting. This amount makes enough for the filling, crumb coat, and for a little piping on top.
Assemble cake and apply crumb coat: Place 1 cake layer on your cake stand, cake turntable, or serving plate. Using a large icing spatula or small offset spatula, evenly cover the top with about 1 cup peanut butter frosting. Repeat with 2nd and 3rd cake layers, spreading about 1 cup of peanut butter frosting in between each layer. Spread a thin layer of frosting on the top and around the sides as a crumb coat. Run a bench scraper around the cake to smooth out crumb coat. Chill uncovered in the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes and up to 3 hours to set the crumb coat.
As your crumb coat sets, make the chocolate ganache: Place finely chopped chocolate in a medium heat-proof bowl. Heat the cream in a small saucepan over medium heat until it begins to gently simmer. (Do not let it come to a rapid boil-that's too hot!) Pour over chocolate, then let it sit for 2-3 minutes to gently soften the chocolate. With a metal spoon or small rubber spatula, very slowly stir until chocolate has melted and mixture is smooth. Ganache is thin. The finer you chopped the chocolate, the quicker it will melt with the cream. If it's not melting, do not microwave it. If needed, see Troubleshooting Chocolate Ganache. Once ganache mixture is smooth, let it chill for 20-30 minutes in the refrigerator to thicken before spreading on chilled crumb-coated cake.
Pour/spoon thickened ganache on chilled cake. Smooth the top with an icing spatula and the sides with a bench scraper. If desired, pipe remaining peanut butter frosting around the edge of the cake. I used Wilton 1M piping tip on the pictured cake. Garnish with peanut butter cups, if desired. Serve cake immediately or chill, uncovered, for up to 4-6 hours before serving. Cake can be served at room temperature or chilled.

Classic Chili

Ingredients

1 tablespoon olive oil
1 medium yellow onion, diced
1 pound 90% lean ground beef
2 1/2 tablespoons chili powder
2 tablespoons ground cumin
2 tablespoons granulated sugar
2 tablespoons tomato paste
1 tablespoon garlic powder
1 1/2 teaspoons salt
1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper
1/4 teaspoon ground cayenne pepper (optional)
1 1/2 cups beef broth
1 (15 oz.) can petite diced tomatoes
1 (16 oz.) can red kidney beans, drained and rinsed
1 (8 oz.) can tomato sauce

Directions

Add the olive oil to a large soup pot and place it over medium-high heat for two minutes. Add the onion. Cook for 5 minutes, stirring occasionally.
Add the ground beef to the pot. Break it apart with a wooden spoon. Cook for 6-7 minutes, until the beef is browned, stirring occasionally.
Add the chili powder, cumin, sugar, tomato paste, garlic powder, salt, pepper, and optional cayenne. Stir until well combined.
Add the broth, diced tomatoes (with their juice), drained beans, and tomato sauce. Stir well.
Bring the liquid to a low boil. Then, reduce the heat (low to medium-low) to gently simmer the chili, uncovered, for 20-25 minutes, stirring occasionally.
Remove the pot from the heat. Let the chili rest for 5-10 minutes before serving.

Cream Cheese Brownies

Ingredients

1/2 cup (4 oz.) unsalted butter
2 cups (12.25 oz.) semisweet chocolate chips
3/4 cup packed light brown sugar
3/4 cup, plus 1/3 cup granulated sugar, divided
5 large eggs, divided, at room temperature
2 1/2 tsp. vanilla extract, divided
1/2 tsp., plus 1/8 tsp. kosher salt, divided
1/2 cup (1.6 oz.) unsweetened cocoa powder
1/2 cup (2.12 oz.) all-purpose flour
8 oz. cream cheese, at room temperature

Directions

Preheat oven to 325 F. Grease a 9x13-inch baking pan with baking spray, and set aside. Gather your ingredients.
In a medium saucepan, melt butter over medium-low until bubbling but not brown.
Turn off heat, add chocolate chips, and stir to coat. Let sit for 5 minutes.
Stir again until the chocolate is completely melted and combined with the butter.
Transfer to a large mixing bowl and add brown sugar, 3/4 cup granulated sugar, 4 eggs, and 2 tsp. vanilla. Whisk until well combined. Add 1/2 tsp. salt, cocoa powder, and flour and stir together until well combined.
Spread batter evenly in prepared baking pan.
With a mixer, beat together cream cheese, 1/3 cup sugar, 1/2 tsp. vanilla, 1/8 tsp. salt, and 1 egg until well combined, about 2 to 3 minutes.
Dollop over top of brownie batter.
Using a knife or small offset spatula, swirl and fold cream cheese into batter; keep tip of knife just about 1/2 inch deep into the brownie batter as much as possible.
Bake until set, a wooden pick inserted in center come out with very moist crumbs, and brownies have started to pull away slightly from edges, about 45 minutes. Allow to cool completely before cutting, about 2 to 3 hours.

Hambagu (Japanese Hamburger Steak)

Ingredients

Patties

1/2 onion, minced
1 Tbsp neutral oil
2 lb ground beef and pork combination
1/2 tsp Diamond Crystal kosher salt
freshly ground black pepper
1/2 tsp nutmeg
1/3 cup panko (Japanese breadcrumbs)
2 Tbsp milk
1 large egg

Tonkatsu Sauce

4 1/2 Tbsp Worcestershire sauce
2 Tbsp sugar (plus more to taste)
5 Tbsp ketchup
2 Tbsp oyster sauce

Directions

Heat a large pan over medium heat. When the pan is hot, add 1 Tbsp neutral oil. Then, add the onions.
Saute the onions until tender and almost translucent. Transfer to a large bowl and let it cool.
Once the onions are cool, mix in ground beef and pork blend, salt, pepper, and nutmeg.
Mix in the panko, milk, and egg, then knead the mixture until it is sticky.
Roll the mixture into balls and then flatten into an oval. Refrigerate for at least 30 minutes.
Add 1 Tbsp neutral oil to a large pan and place the patties. Create indentations in the middle of each patty.
Cook each side until browned. Set patties aside.
Meanwhile, in a small bowl, combine Worcestershire, ketchup, sugar, and oyster sauce to make tonkatsu sauce.
Pour tonkatsu sauce over patties when serving. Serve with steamed rice.

Haupia (Hawaiian Coconut Pudding)

Ingredients

1/2 cup water
5 tablespoons cornstarch
13 ounces unsweetened coconut milk (full-fat ONLY)
1/4 cup sugar

Directions

Combine cornstarch and water in a small bowl. Stir until cornstarch is dissolved then set aside.
In a medium-sized saucepan over medium heat, combine coconut milk and sugar. Whisk constantly until mixture begins to simmer.
While continuing to whisk, SLOWLY pour in the water/cornstarch mixture until it thickens. Reduce heat to low and continue to whisk until you
have a thick, pudding-like consistency. This is important, it needs to be thickened while it is heating or it won't set up.
Pour into a greased 8"x8" baking dish or square containers. I actually like to use my smaller glass Tupperware containers becasue the sides are more straight, making for more consistent squares.
Allow to cool to room temperature, about 10-15 minutes, then cover and refrigerate for 2+ hours.
When ready to serve, cut into 2" squares and serve cold. If serving as a custard or pudding, pour into individual serving ramekins or bowls and chill.

Honey Chicken

Ingredients

Chicken

1 1/2 pounds boneless skinless chicken breasts cut into 1 inch pieces
2 eggs
salt and pepper to taste
1/2 cup all purpose flour
1/2 cup cornstarch
oil for frying canola or vegetable oil
1/4 cup green onions thinly sliced

Sauce

1/2 cup honey
2 tablespoons soy sauce
2 tablespoons water divided use
1/2 teaspoon toasted sesame oil
1 tablespoon apple cider vinegar
1 tablespoon corn starch

Directions

Chicken

Place the eggs, salt and pepper in a bowl. Stir to combine.
Place the flour and 1/2 cup corn starch in a shallow bowl or on a plate. Stir to combine.
Dip each piece of chicken into the egg mixture, then into the flour. Repeat the process with all of the chicken.
Heat 3 inches of oil in a deep pot to 350 degrees F.
Add 7-8 pieces of chicken to the pan. Cook for 5 minutes or until crispy and golden brown. Repeat the process with the remaining chicken.
Drain the chicken on paper towels.

Sauce

While the chicken is cooking, make the sauce. Place the honey, soy sauce, 1 tablespoon of water, sesame oil and apple cider vinegar in a small pan. Bring to a simmer.
Mix the corn starch with the remaining tablespoon of water. Pour the corn starch mixture into the honey mixture.
Bring the sauce to a boil. Cook, stirring constantly, for 1-2 minutes or until sauce has thickened.
Toss the honey sauce with the chicken. Sprinkle with green onions, then serve.

Honey Whole Wheat

Ingredients

Sponge

1 cup (240ml) water, warmed to about 110F (43C)
1/3 cup (80ml) whole milk, warmed to about 110F (43C)
2 and 1/4 teaspoons (7g) active dry or instant yeast (1 standard packet)
2 cups (260g) whole wheat flour (spooned and leveled)

Dough

3 Tablespoons (63g) honey
3 Tablespoons (43g) unsalted butter, softened to room temperature
1 teaspoon fresh lemon juice (or apple cider vinegar)
1 teaspoon sugar
1 and 1/3 cups (173g) whole wheat flour (spooned and leveled), plus more as needed
1 and 1/4 teaspoons salt

Directions

Prepare the sponge: In a large bowl or the bowl of your stand mixer, whisk the water, whole milk, and yeast together. Add the 2 cups (260g) flour and stir with a spatula or wooden spoon until a thick batter forms. Cover lightly and allow to double in size at room temperature, about 60-90 minutes. Sometimes this can take up to 2 hours. I do not recommend a hand mixer for this dough because the dough is too thick and heavy.
Add the remaining dough ingredients including the honey, butter, lemon juice, remaining flour, and the salt. With a dough hook attachment, or using a spatula or wooden spoon (and some arm muscle!), beat on medium speed/mix until the dough comes together and pulls away from the sides of the bowl, about 3 minutes. If the dough seems too wet to a point where kneading (next step) would be impossible, beat in more flour 1 Tablespoon at a time until you have a workable dough, similar to the photos above. Dough should be soft and a little sticky, but still manageable to knead with lightly floured hands.
Knead the dough: Keep the dough in the mixer and beat for an additional 8-10 full minutes, or knead by hand on a lightly floured surface for 8-10 full minutes. (If you're new to bread-baking, my How to Knead Dough video tutorial can help here.) If the dough becomes too sticky during the kneading process, add 1 more Tablespoon of flour at a time to make a soft, slightly tacky dough. Do not add more flour than you need; you do not want a dry dough. After kneading, the dough should still feel a little soft. Poke it with your finger-if it slowly bounces back, your dough is ready to rise.
1st rise: Lightly grease a large bowl with oil or nonstick spray. Place the dough in the bowl, turning it to coat all sides in the oil. Cover the bowl and allow the dough to rise in a relatively warm environment for 1.5-2 hours or until about double in size. Grease a 9x5-inch loaf pan.
Shape the dough: When the dough is ready, punch it down to release the air. Lightly flour a work surface, your hands, and a rolling pin. Roll the dough out into a large rectangle, about 8x15 inches. It does not have to be perfect-in fact, it will probably be rounded on the edges. That's ok! Roll it up into an 8-inch log and place in the prepared loaf pan.
2nd rise: Cover shaped loaf. Allow to rise until it's about 1 inch above the top of the loaf pan, about 45-60 minutes. Adjust oven rack to a lower position and preheat oven to 350F (177C). It's best to bake the bread towards the bottom of the oven so the top doesn't burn.
Bake the bread: Bake for 36-40 minutes, or until golden brown on top. If you notice the top browning too quickly, loosely tent the pan with aluminum foil. (I usually add it around the 20-minute mark.) To test for doneness, if you gently tap on the loaf, it should sound hollow. For a more accurate test, the bread is done when an instant-read thermometer reads the center of the loaf as 195-200F (90-93C). Remove from the oven and allow bread to cool for a few minutes in the pan on a cooling rack before removing the bread from the pan and slicing. Feel free to let it cool completely before slicing, too.
Cover leftover bread tightly and store at room temperature for up to 1 week.

Hot Honey Chicken Sandwich

Ingredients

Hot Honey Sauce

1/4 cup honey
2 tablespoons salted butter
1 tablespoons hot sauce

Chicken

4 boneless, skinless thick chicken thighs (3 to 4 ounces each)
1 cup all-purpose flour
2 tablespoons cornstarch
2 tablespoons chili powder
2 teaspoons onion powder
1 tablespoon kosher salt
1 teaspoon pepper
1 cup buttermilk
3 garlic cloves, minced

Vegetable oil, for frying
4 potato burger buns
14-16 dill pickle chips

Directions

Start by making the sauce. In a small saucepan over low heat, combine the honey, butter and hot sauce. Do not stop stirring until all the butter melts and the honey becomes thin. Set aside.
Prep the chicken. In a medium bowl, whisk together the flour, cornstarch, 1 tablespoon chili powder, onion powder, salt and pepper. In another dish, add the buttermilk, remaining chili powder, and minced garlic. Stir each mixture with a fork until well combined. Marinate the chicken in the buttermilk mixture for 30 minutes. Toss the chicken in the flour, and add on a clean plate. Repeat with the rest.
Heat up the oil. Heat a 2-inch depth of vegetable oil in a heavy large pot between medium and medium high heat. Use a thermometer! Oil must register to 375 F. Add the chicken into the oil and fry, turning once, for about 8 minutes, or until the chicken registers 170 F internal temperature. Transfer to a plate lined with paper towel and repeat with the rest of the chicken. When the chicken cools off a bit, dip into the spicy honey mixture!
Assemble the chicken sandwiches. Add each fried chicken tossed in the honey mixture onto a bun. If you want, you can add mayonnaise as well as the pickles. Top with the bun and enjoy!

Instant Pot Burgers

Ingredients

1 teaspoon salt
1 teaspoon pepper
1 teaspoon smoked paprika
1/4 cup finely diced sweet onion
2 garlic cloves, minced
1 pound 80/20 ground beef
1 tablespoon olive oil
4 hamburger buns, toasted
Toppings: avocado, lettuce, tomato, pickles, mustard, ketchup

Directions

In a large bowl, combine the salt, pepper, paprika, and garlic. Add the meat and gently work the seasoning mixture into the meat. Divide the mixture into 4 equal patties. Place 1 tablespoon minced onion in the center of each patty and fold the onions inside with your thumbs.
Select Saute and preheat the cooking pot. When hot, add the oil and the patties and cook for about 2-3 minutes per side to brown. Transfer to a plate when browned.
Add 1 cup water to the cooking pot, and scrape up any browned bits that may have accumulated on the bottom. Place a trivet in the cooking pot and place the patties on the trivet, leaving space for steam.
Lock the lid in place. Select High Pressure and 6 minutes cook time. When the cook time ends, turn off the pressure cooker. Use a quick pressure release.
When the valve drops, carefully remove the lid.
Serve the burgers on toasted buns topped with avocado and your favorite burger toppings.

Kimchi Spam Fried Rice

Ingredients

2 Tablespoons avocado oil
2 cups ripe kimchi (drained and chopped into bite-sized pieces)
3 Tablespoons kimchi juice
8 oz spam, cubed
3 cups cooked rice (it's best to use leftover cold rice)
1 teaspoon Korean red pepper flakes
1 Tablespoon gochujang (Korean red pepper paste)
1 Tablespoon sesame oil
2 stalks scallions, chopped; for garnish
1 teaspoon toasted sesame seeds, for garnish
1/2 to 1 teaspoon sugar (optional)
4 large eggs, cooked sunny-side up (optional)

Directions

Heat a pan over medium high heat and add about a tablespoon of the oil and the cubed spam. Fry the spam until it's browned and crispy on one side and them flip it over and brown the other side. This should take about 4 to 5 minutes. Remove it from the pan and set it aside.
Add the remaining oil to the pan and add the kimchi, gochujang, and Korean red pepper flakes. Stir fry it together for about 3 to 4 minutes.
Add the day old rice to the pan and break up any large clumps of rice by pressing down with the flat side of your spatula or spoon. Keep stirring together to make sure each grain of rice is coated with the kimchi and oil.
Add the spam back into the pan along with the kimchi juice and sesame oil. Stir fry everything together. Give it a taste at this point to see if the flavors are balanced. If your kimchi is very ripe, it may be too sour and may need a bit of sugar to balance out the flavors. Add sugar if needed and taste again. Otherwise, leave out the sugar. Remove from the heat and portion out the servings.
(Optional) Top with a sunny side up egg and garnish with chopped scallions and sesame seeds. Serve immediately.

Mango Sticky Rice

Ingredients

1 cup Thai sweet rice (aka sticky rice)
1 1/2 cups water, divided
1 (13.5-ounce) can coconut milk, divided
1/4 teaspoon salt
4 to 5 tablespoons brown sugar, to taste, divided
1 to 2 ripe mangoes

Directions

Gather the ingredients.
Soak the rice in 1 cup water in a medium pot for 20 to 30 minutes. Do not drain the rice.
Add 1/2 cup more water, plus 1/2 can of the coconut milk, the salt, and 1 tablespoon of the brown sugar. Stir well. Bring to a gentle boil, then partially cover with a lid (leaving some room for steam to escape). Reduce heat to medium-low, or just until you get a gentle simmer.
Simmer 20 to 30 minutes, or until the coconut water has been absorbed by the rice. Turn off the heat but leave the pot on the burner with the lid on tight. Allow it to sit for 5 to 10 minutes.
To make the sauce, warm (do not boil) the remaining coconut milk over medium-low heat in a small saucepan (about 5 minutes). Add 3 tablespoons brown sugar, stirring to dissolve. Taste-test sauce for sweetness, adding more sugar if desired. (Note that it will not taste as sweet once added to the rice.)
Prepare the mangoes by cutting them open and slicing each into bite-sized pieces.
Scoop some warm rice into each serving bowl, then drizzle lots of the sweet coconut sauce over the top. It should look like an English pudding with custard sauce, with the rice swimming in sauce. Arrange mango slices on the rice and finish with a drizzle of more sauce.

Oatmeal Chocolate Chip Cookies

Ingredients

1 cup all-purpose flour
1/2 tsp baking soda
1/2 tsp salt
1/2 cup unsalted butter room temperature
1/3 cup granulated sugar
2/3 cup light-brown sugar, packed
2 tsp pure vanilla extract
1 large egg
1 1/2 cups rolled oats
1 cup semisweet chocolate chips

Directions

In a medium bowl, whisk together the flour and baking soda; set aside.
Combine the butter with both sugars; beat on medium speed until light and fluffy.
Reduce speed to low; add the salt, vanilla, and eggs. Beat until well mixed, about 1 minute.
Add flour mixture; mix until almost combined.
Stir in the oats and chocolate chips. Chill dough for one hour to overnight.
Preheat oven to 375 degrees.
Use a small ice cream scooper (two tablespoons) to Drop heaping tablespoon-size balls of dough about 2 inches apart on baking sheets lined with parchment paper.
Bake until cookies are golden around the edges, but still soft in the center, 8 to 10 minutes.
Remove from oven, and let cool on baking sheet 1 to 2 minutes. Transfer to a wire rack, and let cool completely.

Peach Cobbler

Ingredients

2 (16-ounce) cans of peaches, drained
1/4 cup white sugar
1/4 cup brown sugar
1/4 teaspoon ground cinnamon
1/8 teaspoon ground nutmeg
1 teaspoon fresh lemon juice
2 teaspoons cornstarch
1 cup all-purpose flour
1/4 cup white sugar
1/4 cup brown sugar
1 teaspoon baking powder
1/2 teaspoon salt
6 tablespoons unsalted butter, chilled and cut into small pieces
1/4 cup boiling water
3 tablespoons white sugar
1 teaspoon ground cinnamon

Directions

Gather all ingredients.
Preheat the oven to 425 degrees F (220 degrees C).
Combine peaches, 1/4 cup white sugar, 1/4 cup brown sugar, 1/4 teaspoon cinnamon, nutmeg, lemon juice, and cornstarch in a large bowl; toss to coat evenly, and pour into a 2-quart baking dish. Bake in preheated oven for 10 minutes.
Meanwhile, combine flour, 1/4 cup white sugar, 1/4 cup brown sugar, baking powder, and salt in a large bowl. Blend in butter with your fingertips or a pastry blender until mixture resembles coarse meal. Stir in water until just combined.
Remove peaches from oven, and drop spoonfuls of topping over them.
Mix 3 tablespoons white sugar and 1 teaspoon cinnamon together in a small bowl; sprinkle over entire cobbler.
Bake in the preheated oven until topping is golden, about 30 minutes.

Philly Cheesesteaks

Ingredients

1 beef top sirloin steak (3 pounds), thinly sliced
2 large onions, cut into 1/2-inch strips
1 can (10-1/2 ounces) condensed French onion soup, undiluted
2 garlic cloves, minced
1 package Italian salad dressing mix
2 teaspoons beef base
1/2 teaspoon pepper
2 large red or green peppers, cut into 1/2-inch strips
1/2 cup pickled pepper rings
8 hoagie buns or French rolls, split
8 slices provolone cheese

Directions

Combine the first 7 ingredients in a 6-qt. electric pressure cooker. Lock lid; close pressure-release valve. Adjust to pressure-cook on high for 10 minutes. Quick-release pressure.
Add peppers and pepper rings. Lock lid; close pressure-release valve. Adjust to pressure-cook on high for an additional 5 minutes. Let pressure release naturally for 10 minutes; quick-release any remaining pressure.
Place bun bottoms on ungreased baking sheets, cut sides up. Using tongs, place beef, vegetables and cheese on bun bottoms. Broil 3-4 in. from heat until cheese is melted, 1-2 minutes. Add bun tops; serve with cooking juices.
Place bun bottoms on ungreased baking sheets, cut sides up. Using tongs, place beef, vegetables and cheese on bun bottoms. Broil 3-4 in. from heat until cheese is melted, 1-2 minutes. Add bun tops; serve with cooking juices.

Pot Roast

Ingredients

1 - 3 pounds (1176g) chuck roast or blade roast , 2 inches thick
1 tablespoon (15ml) olive oil
1 - 2 tablespoons (14g - 28g) unsalted butter or olive oil (optional)
2 (280g) small onions, sliced
6 (20g) garlic cloves, minced
1/4 teaspoon (0.25g) dried rosemary
1/4 teaspoon (0.35g) thyme
2 bay leaves
2 tablespoons (30ml) red wine (Cabernet Sauvignon) or balsamic vinegar
1 cup (250ml) unsalted chicken stock or high-quality unsalted beef stock
1 tablespoon (15ml) regular soy sauce
1 tablespoon (15ml) fish sauce (can substitute with regular soy sauce) (optional)
2 - 4 (750g) potatoes, quartered
3 (280g) medium carrots , cut into 1 1/2 inch (4cm) chunks
Kosher salt and ground black pepper to taste

Thickener

2 tablespoons (18g) cornstarch mixed with 3 tablespoons (45ml) cold water

Directions

Brown Chuck Roast: Heat up Instant Pot using "Saute More" function. Wait until Instant Pot says "HOT" (~8 mins). Pat dry chuck roast with paper towel. Then, generously season one side of chuck roast with kosher salt and ground black pepper. Add 1 tbsp (15ml) olive oil in Instant Pot. Make sure to coat the oil well over the whole bottom of the pot. Place seasoned side of chuck roast in Instant Pot, then season the other side of chuck roast with more kosher salt and ground black pepper. Let chuck roast brown for 8 minutes per side to develop some deep flavors. Don't need to constantly flip the chuck roast. When the chuck roast is nice and browned, remove it and set aside.
Saute Onions and Garlic: Add in sliced onions, then saute for 3 minutes until softened. Add in minced garlic, 1/4 tsp (0.25g) dried rosemary, 1/4 tsp (0.35g) thyme, and 2 bay leaves, then saute for another minute.
Deglaze Instant Pot: Pour in 2 tbsp (30ml) red wine (Cabernet Sauvignon) or balsamic vinegar, then deglaze by scrubbing all the flavorful brown bits off the bottom of the pot with a wooden spoon.
Pressure Cook Pot Roast: Add 1 cup (250ml) unsalted chicken stock, 1 tbsp (15ml) regular soy sauce, and 1 tbsp (15ml) fish sauce in Instant Pot. Place browned chuck roast in Instant Pot. Don't forget to add in all the meat juice! Make sure the chuck roast is at least partially submerged in the cooking liquid. With Venting Knob in Venting Position, close the lid, then turn Venting Knob to Sealing Position. Pressure Cook at High Pressure for 45 minutes, then Full Natural Release for 25 minutes. Open the lid carefully.
Pressure Cook Vegetables: Set aside chuck roast. Let it rest as you pressure cook the vegetables. Submerge quartered potatoes into the sauce, then stack chopped carrots on top of the potatoes. With Venting Knob in Venting Position, close the lid, then turn Venting Knob to Sealing Position. Pressure cook at High Pressure for 4 minutes, then Quick Release. Open the lid carefully.
Make Gravy and Serve: Taste the sauce, then adjust the seasoning if necessary. Mix 2 tbsp (18g) cornstarch with 3 tbsp (45ml) cold water, then mix it into the sauce one third at a time until desired thickness.

Potatoes Au Gratin

Ingredients

3-4 Russet pototes or 7-8 Yukon Gold potatoes
1/2 medium onion, sliced
Salt and pepper to taste
3 tablespoons butter
3 tablespoons all-purpose flour
1/2 teaspoon salt
2 cups milk
1-2 cups shredded cheese, such as sharp cheddar, Gruyere, or Colby-Jack

Directions

Preheat the oven to 400 degrees F (200 degrees C). Butter a 1-quart casserole dish.
Layer 1/2 of the potatoes in the bottom of the prepared casserole dish; season with salt and pepper. Layer onion slices over top, then top with with remaining potatoes. Season again with salt and pepper.
Melt butter in a medium saucepan over medium heat. Gradually whisk in flour and salt and cook, whisking constantly until raw flour flavor has cooked off, about 1 minute. Gradually add milk, about 1/4 cup at a time, whisking well after each addition to incorporate; the gradual addition and whisking of milk will help avoid lumps in your sauce.
Cook, whisking constantly, until the mixture has thickened, 3 to 5 minutes. Stir in cheese all at once; continue stirring until melted, 30 to 60 seconds. Pour cheese sauce over the potatoes.
Bake in the preheated oven until potatoes are tender and sauce is bubbly, about 60-90 minutes.

Pumpkin Cheesecake

Ingredients

Cheesecake Layer

2 (8 ounce) packages cream cheese, softened
1/2 cup white sugar
1/2 teaspoon vanilla extract
2 large eggs
1 (9 inch) prepared graham cracker crust

Pumpkin Layer

1/2 cup pumpkin puree
1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon
1 pinch ground cloves, or more to taste
1 pinch ground nutmeg, or more to taste

Directions

Preheat the oven to 325 degrees F (165 degrees C).
Make cheesecake layer: Beat cream cheese, sugar, and vanilla in a large bowl with an electric mixer until smooth. Add eggs, one at a time, blending well after each addition.
Spread 1 cup batter in the graham cracker crust.
Make pumpkin layer: Add pumpkin puree, cinnamon, cloves, and nutmeg to the remaining batter; stir gently until well blended.
Carefully spread on top of plain cheesecake batter in the crust.
Bake in the preheated oven until the edges are puffed and the surface is firm except for a small spot in the center that jiggles when the pan is gently shaken, 35 to 40 minutes.
Remove from the oven, set on a wire rack, and cool to room temperature, 1 to 2 hours.
Refrigerate for at least 3 hours before serving, preferably overnight.

Shrimp and Grits

Ingredients

1/2-3/4 pound deveined and shelled shrimp
2 tablespoons Olive oil
2 teaspoons Old Bay seasoning
1 teaspoon Italian seasoning
1/4 teaspoon garlic powder
1/4 teaspoon smoked paprika
2 cups chicken broth
1/2 cup yellow corn grits
2 ounces cream cheese
1 cup shredded sharp cheddar cheese
2 green onion stalks, chopped
2 slices bacon
salt and pepper to taste

Directions

In a large skillet cook two slices of bacon over medium heat until crisp, remove bacon from skillet, roughly chop. Wipe skillet clean and set aside to use later for the shrimp.
In a medium to large sauce pan bring chicken broth to a boil, add grits and reduce heat to low. Cover and let grits simmer for 7 minutes, stirring occasionally.
When grits have absorbed the liquid add cream cheese, shredded cheese and salt and pepper to taste.
Stir mixture well, cover and remove from heat.
Place shrimp in a large plastic bag or mixing bowl, add Old Bay, Italian seasoning, garlic powder and smoked paprika and toss until shrimp is coated.
Heat olive oil in a large pan over medium high heat. Add shrimp and cook 3 minutes on each side or until shrimp is pink and tender.
To assemble the shrimp and grits add a heaping serving of grits to two shallow bowls. Top with shrimp, chopped green onions, chopped bacon and additional pepper.

Shrimp Boil Skillet

Ingredients

4 quarts hot water
1 large red onion or yellow onion, sliced into 4 - 6 wedges
1 garlic bulb (whole head), halved horizontally
1/2 cup Old Bay seasoning
1 1/2 Tbsp fresh thyme leaves (or 1 1/2 tsp dried)
1 1/2 lbs medium red potatoes, cut into fourths
Salt and pepper to taste
4 ears corn, husked, cut onto fourths or broken into halves
14 oz. andouille sausage, sliced into 1-inch thick pieces
1 1/2 lbs shrimp, deveined, peeled if preferred
6 Tbsp unsalted butter, melted
2 Tbsp fresh lemon juice, or more to taste
2 Tbsp minced fresh parsley

Directions

Fill a large pot (about 12 quart) with 4 quarts water. Stir in onion, garlic, Old Bay seasoning, and thyme. Bring mixture to a boil over medium-high heat.
Add potatoes and season with salt (I use 1 Tbsp). Let cook until potatoes are about nearing tender, about 10 - 15 minutes.
Add corn and continue to cook 3 minutes. Add sausage and cook 4 minutes longer.
Gently stir in shrimp and cook until just opaque and pink, about 1 - 2 minutes.
Drain mixture (you can reserve 1/4 cup of the broth if you'd like for serving). Spread over an extra large serving platter or a baking sheet.
Drizzle with butter and lemon juice. Sprinkle with parsley, Old Bay seasoning and pepper to taste, and serve warm.

Skillet Pork Chops

Ingredients

4 pork chops, about 1-inch thick and 6 to 7 ounces each, see notes
Salt, to taste
1 tablespoon all-purpose flour
1 teaspoon chili powder
1 teaspoon garlic powder
1 teaspoon onion powder
1/2 teaspoon smoked paprika
1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper
1 tablespoon neutral oil, such as avocado oil or vegetable oil
1 cup low-sodium chicken stock
1 tablespoon apple cider vinegar
2 teaspoons honey or brown sugar
1 tablespoon butter
2 tablespoons chopped fresh parsley, optional

Directions

Pork Chops

Take the pork chops out of the refrigerator and season on both sides with salt. Set the chops aside to rest for 30 minutes.
Meanwhile, make the spice rub. In a small bowl, mix the flour, chili powder, garlic powder, onion powder, smoked paprika, and 1/2 teaspoon of black pepper.
After 30 minutes, use a paper towel to pat the pork chops dry, then rub both sides of the chops with the spice rub.
Heat the oil in a skillet (with a lid) over medium-high heat. When the oil is hot and looks shimmery, add the pork. Cook until golden, 2 to 3 minutes.
Flip the pork so that the seared side is facing up. If there is a fattier side of the pork, use kitchen tongs to hold the chops, fat-side-down until it sizzles and browns slightly; about 30 seconds.
Reduce the heat to low, then cover the skillet with a lid. Cook 6 to 12 minutes or until an instant-read thermometer reads 145 degrees F when inserted into the thickest part of the chop. Cook time depends on the thickness of the chops, so check for doneness at 5 minutes, then go from there, checking every 2 minutes after that. If you do not have a thermometer, you will know they are done, if, when cutting into the chops, the juices run clear.
Transfer pork chops to a plate. Let the pork rest for 5 minutes.

Sauce

While the pork rests, make the pan sauce. Increase the heat to medium-high, then add the chicken stock, vinegar, and honey. Use a wooden spoon to scrape the bottom of the pan so that any stuck bits of pork come up.
Bring the sauce to a simmer and cook until reduced by half. Taste, then adjust the seasoning with additional salt, vinegar, or honey.
Slide the skillet off of the heat and when the sauce is no longer simmering, swirl in the butter.
Slide the pork chops back into the pan and spoon some of the sauce on top. Alternatively, slice the chops, then place them back into the pan. Scatter fresh parsley over the pork, and then serve.

Sloppy Joes

Ingredients

Sloppy Joes

1 Tbsp extra-virgin olive oil, 1 turn of the pan
1 lb ground beef sirloin
1/4 c brown sugar
1 Tbsp steak seasoning blend, such as mccormick brand montreal seasoning
1 md onion
1 sm red bell pepper, chopped
1 Tbsp red wine vinegar
1 Tbsp worcestershire sauce
2 c tomato sauce
2 Tbsp tomato paste
4 crusty rolls, split, toasted, and lightly buttered

Potato Salad

5 potatoes, peeled and diced
coarse salt
3 Tbsp prepared yellow mustard
1/2 c mayonnaise, eyeball the amount
1 tsp sweet paprika
1 tsp hot cayenne pepper sauce (recommended: Tabasco or Frank's Red Hot)
2 scallions, thinly sliced, for garnish
salt and pepper to taste

Directions

Sloppy Joes

Heat a large skillet over medium high heat. Add oil and meat to the pan.
Spread the meat around the pan and begin to break it up.
Combine brown sugar and steak seasoning. Add sugar and spice mixture to the skillet and combine.
When the meat has browned, add onion and red peppers to the skillet. Reduce heat to medium and cook onions, peppers, red wine vinegar and Worcestershire sauce with meat for 5 minutes.
Add tomato sauce and paste to pan. Stir to combine. Reduce heat to simmer and cook sloppy joe mixture 5 minutes longer.
Using a large spoon or ice cream scoop, pile sloppy meat onto toasted, buttered bun bottoms and cover with bun tops. Serve with your favorite sides or sliced tomatoes seasoned with salt and pepper, dill pickles and potato salad.

Potato Salad

Boil potatoes in water seasoned with coarse salt until they are tender, about 10 minutes. Drain cooked potatoes and return to the warm pot to dry them out. Let the potatoes stand 2 minutes, then spread potatoes out on to a cookie sheet to quick-cool them.
In the bottom of a medium mixing bowl, grate 1/4 onion using a hand grater. Add mustard and mayonnaise, paprika and cayenne pepper sauce to the grated onion and stir to combine.
Add potatoes to the bowl and stir to evenly distribute dressing. Season potato salad with salt and pepper and taste to adjust your seasonings. Top servings of salad with chopped scallions.

Smoked Sausage and Pineapple

Ingredients

2 lbs smoked sausage
20 oz can pineapple chunks
3 tablespoon teriyaki sauce
2 tablespoon chili sauce
1 tablespoon honey
1 tbsp pineapple juice, from the can
Toothpicks, for serving

Directions

Pre-heat oven to 425 degrees F.
Remove sausage from packaging and slice it into 1-inch pieces. Place sausage in a 9x13 baking pan. Drain pineapple juice, but reserve about a tablespoon to use for the sauce. Add pineapple to the pan with the sliced sausage.
In a small bowl or a glass measuring cup, mix together the teriyaki sauce, chili sauce, honey, and pineapple juice. Pour sauce over sausage and pineapple. Gently stir to coat the sausage and pineapple in the sauce.
Bake uncovered for 10 minutes. Gently stir the sausage and pineapple. Bake for an additional 10 minutes, and remove from the oven.
The appetizer can be served in the pan with toothpicks. These can be assembled prior to serving as well. Assemble by placing a pineapple chunk on the toothpick followed by a piece of sausage, and transfer to a serving platter. Serve warm.

Stovetop Macaroni and Cheese

Ingredients

1 pound uncooked pasta
3 cups water
2 cups milk
1 teaspoon Dijon mustard
1 teaspoon fine sea salt
1 teaspoon garlic powder
2 to 4 cups (8 to 16 ounces) freshly-grated sharp cheddar cheese
1 cup (1 ounce) finely-grated Parmesan cheese
freshly-ground black pepper, to taste

Directions

Cook the pasta. Combine the pasta, water, milk, Dijon, sea salt and garlic powder in a large stockpot. Heat over medium-high heat, stirring the pasta once every few minutes, until the water reaches a boil. Adjust heat as needed to maintain a rolling boil. Continue cooking the pasta, stirring once or twice per minute, until the pasta is just barely al dente. (Cooking time will depend on the shape of pasta that you use, so please keep a close eye on it.) Remove pot from heat.
Remove excess water (if needed). Check to see how much starchy pasta water remains in the pot. If it seems that there is more than 1/2 cup or so, dip a heatproof measuring cup in to remove and save the excess water, then set it to the side. (If by chance there is no starchy pasta water left, please add 1/2 cup hot water to the pot.)
Add cheese. Add the cheese to the pasta and gently stir until completely melted. If the pasta seems too dry, stir some of the reserved starchy pasta water back in as needed.
Season. Taste and season with additional salt if needed.
Serve. Serve warm, garnished with a few twists of black pepper and enjoy!

Swedish Meatballs

Ingredients

Meatballs

1/4 cup plain breadcrumbs
1/4 tsp ground nutmeg
1/4 tsp allspice
1/4 tsp garlic powder
1/2 tsp salt
1 lb. ground beef and pork blend
1/2 yellow onion, grated
1 large egg, lightly whisked
1 Tbsp vegetable oil

Cream Sauce

3 Tbsp butter
4 Tbsp all-purpose flour
2 cups beef broth
1 tsp Worcestershire sauce
1/4 tsp black pepper
1/8 tsp ground nutmeg
1/3 cup heavy cream
1 Tbsp fresh parsley

Directions

Gather and prepare all ingredients.
To make the meatballs, in a medium bowl, combine the breadcrumbs, tsp nutmeg, allspice, garlic powder, and salt.
Meanwhile, add the beef and pork blend and grated onions to a large bowl. Lightly whisk the egg, then add it to the bowl with the meat. Lastly, add the breadcrumb mixture.
Use your hands to mix the meat and seasonings until evenly combined, but avoid overmixing.
Evenly divide and shape the meat mixture into 16 meatballs, about 1.5 Tbsp each, packing tightly.
Add the vegetable oil to a large skillet and heat over medium. Once hot, carefully add the meatballs. Cook for three minutes on each side, or until well browned. The meatballs do not need to be cooked through at this point. Remove the browned meatballs from the skillet and set aside.
Add the butter and the flour to the skillet. Whisk the butter and flour together as the butter melts. Cook the butter and flour mixture for about two minutes.
Slowly whisk in the beef broth, making sure to release all of the browned bits off the bottom of the skillet. Allow the broth to come up to a simmer, at which point it will thicken, 3-5 minutes.
Stir in the Worcestershire sauce, pepper, nutmeg, and heavy cream. Taste the cream sauce and adjust the salt or seasonings to your liking.
Return the meatballs to the skillet and stir to coat in the sauce. Heat the meatballs over low, stirring occasionally, until heated through, about 5 minutes.
Garnish with fresh parsley and enjoy.

Sweet and Sour Pork

Ingredients

2 tablespoons plus 1-1/2 teaspoons paprika
1-1/2 pounds boneless pork loin roast, cut into 1-inch strips
1 tablespoon canola oil
1 can (20 ounces) unsweetened pineapple chunks
1 medium onion, chopped
1 medium green pepper, chopped
1/4 cup cider vinegar
3 tablespoons packed brown sugar
3 tablespoons reduced-sodium soy sauce
1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce
1/2 teaspoon salt
2 tablespoons cornstarch
1/4 cup cold water
Thinly sliced / chopped green onions, optional
Hot cooked rice (optional)

Directions

Place paprika in a large shallow dish. Add pork, a few pieces at a time, and turn to coat. Select saute setting on a 6-qt. electric pressure cooker and adjust for medium heat; add oil. Brown pork in batches. Return all pork to pressure cooker.
Drain pineapple, reserving juice; refrigerate the pineapple. Add the pineapple juice, onion, green pepper, vinegar, brown sugar, soy sauce, Worcestershire sauce and salt to pressure cooker. Lock lid; close pressure-release valve. Adjust to pressure-cook on high for 10 minutes. Quick-release pressure.
Select saute setting and adjust for high heat; bring liquid to a boil. In a small bowl, mix cornstarch and water until smooth; gradually stir into pork mixture. Add pineapple. Cook and stir until sauce is thickened, 1-2 minutes. If desired, sprinkle with green onions and serve over rice.

Teriyaki Chicken

Ingredients

1 1/2 pounds boneless, skinless chicken breasts about 3 medium breasts
2/3 cup low-sodium soy sauce (or tamari, for gluten free)
1/3 cup water
3 tablespoons rice vinegar
3 tablespoons honey
3 tablespoons brown sugar
2 cloves garlic, minced
2 tablespoons fresh ginger, minced
3 tablespoons cornstarch, stirred together with 1/4 cup water to create a slurry

Directions

Lightly coat the bottom of a 6-quart Instant Pot with nonstick spray. Arrange the chicken breasts in the bottom.
In a medium-size bowl, whisk together the soy sauce, water, rice vinegar, honey, brown sugar, garlic, and ginger. Pour over the chicken.
Close and seal the Instant Pot. Cook on HIGH (manual) pressure for 10 minutes. Let the pressure release naturally for 5 minutes, then immediately vent to release the remaining pressure. Carefully open the lid. Turn the Instant Pot OFF. Transfer the chicken to a plate and let it cool for a few minutes.
Once you can safely handle it, shred the chicken with two forks or cut it into bite-size pieces.
Turn the Instant Pot to SAUTE. Once the liquid begins to simmer, slowly whisk in the cornstarch slurry. Continue whisking to ensure the sauce is smooth and does not have any lumps. Continue to cook and whisk until the sauce thickens, about 1 to 2 minutes.
Turn the Instant Pot OFF. Add the chicken back to the pot and toss to coat in the sauce. Serve hot with prepared rice and a sprinkle of green onions and sesame seeds.

Tomato and Egg Stir Fry

Ingredients

4 medium ripe tomatoes
4 eggs
2 tablespoon neutral cooking oil, divided
3 cloves garlic, sliced
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 pinch sugar
1/2 stalk scallions, finely chopped

Directions

Remove the stems of the tomatoes, then cut them into bite-sized pieces. Optionally, remove their skin beforehand.
Crack the eggs into a bowl and add 2 tablespoons of water. Beat until the whites and yolks are well integrated.
Heat 1 1/2 tablespoons of oil in a skillet/frying pan over high heat until very hot.
Pour in the beaten egg. Allow the bottom part to set first. Then move with a spatula so that the running part flows to the hot surface to cook. Break the scrambled egg into bite-sized pieces then transfer out to a plate.
Add the remaining 1/2 tablespoon of oil to the same skillet/pan/wok. Fry sliced garlic over medium heat until fragrant (do not burn).
Put in the chopped tomato. Stir-fry for 20 seconds or so. Add 1/4 cup of water. Leave to cook until the tomato becomes a little mushy.
Add the scrambled egg. Sprinkle salt, sugar and scallions over. Give everything a quick stir to combine. Dish out and serve immediately with steamed rice, or as a topping for noodles.